<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata [
	<!ENTITY ge "&#8805;">
	<!ENTITY le "&#8804;">
	<!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;">
	<!ENTITY radic "&#8730;">
	<!ENTITY sup2 "&#178;">
	<!ENTITY sigma "&#963;">
]>
<metadata>
 <idinfo>
  <citation>
   <citeinfo>
    <origin>Electoral Geography Division - Elections Canada</origin>
    <pubdate>March 2014</pubdate>
    <title>FED_CA_2_0_EN</title>
    <edition>2.0</edition>
    <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
    <pubinfo>
     <pubplace>Ottawa</pubplace>
     <publish>Electoral Geography Division - Elections Canada</publish>
    </pubinfo>
    <onlink>http://geobase.ca/geobase/fr/data/admin/fed/description.html</onlink>
   </citeinfo>
  </citation>
  <descript>
   <abstract>Canada is divided into 338 electoral districts. A representative or member of Parliament is elected for each electoral district.

Following the release of population counts from each decennial census, the Chief Electoral Officer determines the number of seats in the House of Commons and publishes the information in the Canada Gazette. Electoral boundaries commissions then determine the adjustments to the constituency boundaries. The federal electoral boundaries commissions are independent bodies that make all decisions regarding the proposed and final federal electoral boundaries.

Elections Canada provides support services to the boundaries commission in each province.

Based on reports from these commissions, the Chief Electoral Officer prepares a representation order that describes the boundaries and specifies the name and the population of each FED. The representation order is in force on the first dissolution of Parliament that occurs at least seven months after its proclamation. The 2013 Representation Order (proclaimed on October 5, 2013) was based on 2011 Census population counts, and increased the number of FEDs to 338, up from 308 from the previous 2003 Representation Order. Ontario received fifteen additional seats, Alberta and British Columbia each gained six seats while Quebec added three seats. The names of FEDs may change at any time through an Act of Parliament.</abstract>
   <purpose>To provide the public with a digital representation of the 338 electoral district boundaries.  This dataset is not to be used for defining or delineating boundaries that would normally be described by legal documents and/or legal survey plans.</purpose>
  </descript>
  <timeperd>
   <timeinfo>
     <sngdate>
      <caldate>2014</caldate>
     </sngdate>
   </timeinfo>
   <current>March 2014</current>
  </timeperd>
  <status>
   <progress>complete</progress>
   <update>As needed</update>
  </status>
  <spdom>
   <bounding>
    <westbc>-141</westbc>
    <eastbc>-53.7</eastbc>
    <northbc>83.3</northbc>
    <southbc>42.4</southbc>
   </bounding>
  </spdom>
  <keywords>
   <theme>
     <themekt>GCMD</themekt>
     <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Human Dimensions &gt; Boundaries &gt; Political Divisions</themekey>
   </theme>
   <place>
     <placekt>CEONET</placekt>
     <placekey>Canada</placekey>
   </place>
  </keywords>
  <accconst>Use of the GeoBase data is subject to the Open Government Licence - Canada.</accconst>
  <useconst>Use of the GeoBase data is subject to the Open Government Licence - Canada.</useconst>
  <ptcontac>
   <cntinfo>
     <cntorgp>
      <cntorg>Elections Canada</cntorg>
      <cntper>Electoral Geography Division</cntper>
     </cntorgp>
    <cntaddr>
     <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
     <address>257 Slater Street</address>
     <city>Ottawa</city>
     <state>Ontario</state>
     <postal>K1A0M6</postal>
     <country>Canada</country>
    </cntaddr>
    <cntvoice>1-800-463-6868</cntvoice>
    <cntfax>613-954-8584</cntfax>
    <cntemail>geoservices@elections.ca</cntemail>
   </cntinfo>
  </ptcontac>
  <datacred>Electoral Geography Division - Elections Canada </datacred>
 </idinfo>
 <dataqual>
  <attracc>
   <attraccr>The domain values assigned to the item fields of the FED dataset are validated against those domain values described in the Federal Electoral Districts Feature Catalogue. </attraccr>
  </attracc>
  <logic>The delineation of the FED boundaries was created in reference to the National Geographic Database (NGD) road network and the NGD reference base layers. The representation of the digital electoral districts abides by the official boundary definition as established by the 2013 federal electoral boundaries commissions, as amended.

The FED dataset provides for complete national coverage of the entire country. There are no gaps or overlays between any of the FED polygon features present in any of the datasets.

The conceptual model of the FED data is presented in the document Federal Electoral Districts: Conceptual Data Model accessible on the GeoBase portal (www.geobase.ca).</logic>
  <complete>The FED dataset provides complete national coverage for the whole of Canada; this includes the 10 provinces and three northern territories. All polygon features are linked to a corresponding attribute record.</complete>
  <posacc>
   <horizpa>
    <horizpar>The absolute external positional accuracy describes the degree to which the position of features in a geographic database reflects their true position on the ground. It is the difference in the distances measured between two known points on a map and the true distances between the same two points, as established by conventional surveying methods.

The absolute positional accuracy of the spatial entities comprising the FED dataset is dependent on the absolute accuracy of the different feature sets used in the creation of the FED boundaries. Federal electoral districts are derived by performing a spatial dissolve of the electoral polling divisions within each electoral district. The spatial elements that are used to represent a polling division boundary include both human-made features such as roads, railways, power lines and other natural features such as lakes, shorelines and rivers. In addition, many boundary elements follow survey lines, such as those defining the limits for a town, county or township.

Additional information on the positional accuracy of the FED digital dataset and the data features used in the creation of the electoral district boundaries can be found at http://dsp-psd.pwgsc.gc.ca/collection_2009/statcan/92-500-G/92-500-g2009001-eng.pdf.

The base features that define a poll division are derived from multiple data sources, including both digital and paper maps based on 1:10 000 to 1:1 000 000 scale source data. Some of these data sources have known levels of positional accuracy while others do not. Ongoing maintenance and update processes have introduced additional levels of spatial inaccuracies into the datasets.

In this context, it is impossible to accurately ascribe a level of positional accuracy to the dataset. All that can be stated about the data is that for most urban and built-up areas, data were sourced from 1:50 000 data (accuracy ±10 metres); rural areas in southern parts of Canada were sourced using data from 1:250 000 data (accuracy ±300 metres); and the northern areas of Canada used data from 1:1 000 000 (accuracy ±2100 to ±4300 metres).

There are also digital elements sourced from the NGD road network whose positional accuracy cannot be described. These arc elements were digitized on screen from paper maps, and although accurate in their attribute information and their relative position in relation to other map features, the absolute positional accuracy of these FED road network-derived elements cannot be accurately quantified.</horizpar>
   </horizpa>
  </posacc>
  <lineage>
   <srcinfo>
    <srcscale>1:50,000, 1:250,000, 1:1,000,000</srcscale>
    <typesrc>online</typesrc>
    <srccitea>EGD</srccitea>
    <srccontr>The FED dataset is created by performing a spatial dissolve on the polling division boundaries associated with each main electoral district. The underlying boundary elements that make up a polling division are derived from various base-layer features, including the road network, hydrographic features and other human-made features such as railways, power transmission lines and municipal limits. The accuracy of individual boundary features found in the electoral district dataset is therefore associated with the accuracy of the base-layer elements from which they were derived.</srccontr>
   </srcinfo>
   <procstep>
    <procdesc>The FED dataset is created by performing a spatial dissolve on the polling division boundaries associated with each main electoral district. The underlying boundary elements that make up a polling division are derived from various base-layer features, including the road network, hydrographic features and other human-made features such as railways, power transmission lines and municipal limits. The accuracy of individual boundary features found in the electoral district dataset is therefore associated with the accuracy of the base-layer elements from which they were derived.

The base features that define a poll division are derived from multiple data sources, including both digital and paper maps based on 1:10 000 to 1:1 000 000 scale source data. Some of these data sources have known levels of positional accuracy while others do not. Ongoing maintenance and update processes have introduced additional levels of spatial inaccuracies into the datasets.

In this context, it is impossible to accurately ascribe a level of positional accuracy to the dataset. All that can be stated about the data is that for most urban and built-up areas, data were sourced from 1:50 000 data (accuracy ±10 metres); rural areas in southern parts of Canada were sourced using data from 1:250 000 data (accuracy ±300 metres); and the northern areas of Canada used data from 1:1 000 000 (accuracy ±2100 to ±4300 metres).

There are also digital elements sourced from the NGD road network whose positional accuracy cannot be described. These arc elements were digitized on screen from paper maps, and although accurate in their attribute information and their relative position in relation to other map features, the absolute positional accuracy of these FED road network-derived elements cannot be accurately quantified.</procdesc>
   </procstep>
  </lineage>
 </dataqual>
 <spdoinfo>
   <direct>vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>338</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
 </spdoinfo>
 <spref>
  <horizsys>
    <planar>
      <mapproj>
       <mapprojn>Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn>
        <lambertc>
         <stdparll>49.000000</stdparll>
         <stdparll>77.000000</stdparll>
         <longcm>-91.866667</longcm>
         <latprjo>63.390675</latprjo>
         <feast>6200000.000000</feast>
         <fnorth>3000000.000000</fnorth>
        </lambertc>
      </mapproj>
     <planci>
      <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
       <coordrep>
        <absres>0.002857 </absres>
        <ordres>0.002857 </ordres>
       </coordrep>
      <plandu>meters</plandu>
     </planci>
    </planar>
   <geodetic>
    <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
   </geodetic>
  </horizsys>
  <vertdef>
   <altsys>
    <altres>1.000000</altres>
    <altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
   </altsys>
  </vertdef>
 </spref>
 <distinfo>
   <distrib>
    <cntinfo>
      <cntorgp>
       <cntorg>GeoBase Technical Support</cntorg>
       <cntper>    Centre for Topographic Information - Sherbrooke</cntper>
      </cntorgp>
     <cntaddr>
      <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
      <address>    2144, King Street West, Suite 010</address>
      <city>Sherbrooke</city>
      <state>Quebec</state>
      <postal>J1J2E8</postal>
      <country>Canada</country>
     </cntaddr>
     <cntvoice>    +01-819-564-4857 / 1-800-661-2638 (Canada and USA)</cntvoice>
     <cntfax>+01-819-564-5698</cntfax>
     <cntemail>    SupportGeoBase@NRCan.gc.ca </cntemail>
     <hours>8:30 to 12:00 and 13:00 to 16:30 EST</hours>
    </cntinfo>
   </distrib>
   <stdorder>
     <digform>
      <digtinfo>
       <formname>Shapefiles - ESRI</formname>
      </digtinfo>
      <digtopt>
        <onlinopt>
         <computer>
           <networka>
            <networkr>http://www.geobase.ca</networkr>
           </networka>
         </computer>
        </onlinopt>
      </digtopt>
     </digform>
     <digform>
      <digtinfo>
       <formname>    GML - Geography Markup Language</formname>
      </digtinfo>
      <digtopt>
        <onlinopt>
         <computer>
           <networka>
            <networkr>http://www.geobase.ca</networkr>
           </networka>
         </computer>
        </onlinopt>
      </digtopt>
     </digform>
     <digform>
      <digtinfo>
       <formname>KML (Keyhole Markup Language)</formname>
      </digtinfo>
      <digtopt>
        <onlinopt>
         <computer>
           <networka>
            <networkr>http://www.geobase.ca</networkr>
           </networka>
         </computer>
        </onlinopt>
      </digtopt>
     </digform>
    <fees>Gratuit-Free</fees>
   </stdorder>
 </distinfo>
 <metainfo>
  <metd>2010-03-09</metd>
  <metc>
   <cntinfo>
     <cntorgp>
      <cntorg>Elections Canada</cntorg>
      <cntper>Electoral Geography Division</cntper>
     </cntorgp>
    <cntaddr>
     <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
     <address>257 Slater Street</address>
     <city>Ottawa</city>
     <state>Ontario</state>
     <postal>K1A0M6</postal>
     <country>Canada</country>
    </cntaddr>
    <cntvoice>+01-800-463-6868</cntvoice>
    <cntfax>+01-613-954-8584</cntfax>
    <cntemail>geoservices@elections.ca </cntemail>
    <hours>8:00 - 16:00</hours>
   </cntinfo>
  </metc>
  <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
  <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
 </metainfo>
</metadata>
